Industrial civil engineer from UTFSM, with five years of experience in business intelligence and data analytics. I have dexterity applying machine learning and data science techniques. I have experience developing projects associated with the processes of generation key business information. I am characterized by being a creative, curious, autonomous, proactive, responsible, empathetic and insightful leader. I am passionate about teamwork, programming, strategy, odds, and statistics.

Experience

I. Especialista control de riesgo | BancoEstado Microempresas | Mzo 2017 – Ene 2019

Responsibilities: Generation diagnoses of the evolution of the risk of the balances associated with clients throughout the country grouped according to office, segments and product. These diagnoses were presented to the branchs management who are responsible for managing the risk.

Responsible for creating and updating analytical bases used to generate monthly reports the risk evolution of pre-approved, semi-pre-approved and mortgage products. These reports was sented to entire risk area.

Main achievement: Develop a mathematical model to determine monthly how many new clients have to be financed by each offices to reach the goal determined by the management by the year 2021. To do this, I modeled the factors that decreased clients such as default, full payment before calendar, and payment according to calendar. In addition, I determined the sensibility of the result against each factor, this was used to define the strategy to minimize the decrease of customers.

II. Ingeniero de inteligencia de negocios | TrioGroup | Ago 2013 – May 2015

Responsibilities: Make a model of segmentation and classification of clients to apply CRM strategy focused on build customer loyalty. Responsible for analyzing the databases generated in SAP and controlling the main KPIs created from them. Also, it participated monthly in the creation of the balance sheet, providing the information on production costs.

Main achievements: Lead the implementation of SAP in the production area, I participated in the creation of a KDD process applied to production costs, thanks to which production losses and inventory stock differences decreased.

III. Ingeniero de Control de gestión | TrioGroup | Ene 2013 – Jul 2013

Responsibilities: Responsible for analyzing the company's production, and planning and supervising investment projects in technological equipment to improve productive efficiency.

Main achievements: I successfully evaluated and executed improvement projects in the production area to optimize the use of inputs and energy, which generated an increase in the margin.

Education

- I. Industrial civil engineering | U. T. Federico Santa María | Titled (Mzo 2008 Myo 2014)
- II. Business Intelligence Diploma | U. de Chile | Approved (Ago 2015 Ene 2016)

Certifications

- I. Deep Learning | IBM | Oct 2019
- II. Data Science | IBM | Abr 2020

Technical skills

Softwares / Platforms / Application	Level		
	Mdo	Avd	Exp
Excel			\times
M. SQL Server		\times	
SAS / Rapidminer	\times		
Power BI / Tableau	\times		
IBM Watson Studio			
Jupyter			

Programming languages	Level			
	Mdo	Avd	Exp	
SQL			\times	
Python		\times		
R	\times			

Mdo: Medium | Avd: Advanced | Exp: Expert.

Courses

- I. Machine Learning with Python | IBM
- III. Data visualization with Python | IBM
- V. Deep Learning with Tensorflow | IBM
- VII. Deep Learning with Python & Pytorch | IBM
- IX. Deep Learning Fundamentals with Keras | IBM
- XI. Joining Data in PostgreSQL | Datacamp
- XIII. Data Analysis and statistical inference | Dtcmp.
- XV. Credit Risk Modeling in R | Datacamp

- II. Data Analysis with Python | IBM
- IV. Open Source tools for Data Science | IBM
- VI. Using GPU to Scale and Speed -up DL | IBM
- VIII. Python for Data Science and AI | IBM
- X. Databases and SQL for Data Science | IBM
- XII. Data Science Methodology | IBM
- XIV. R for SAS, SPSS and STATA Users | Datacamp
- XVI. SQL for Exloratory Data Analysis | Datacamp